<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
 version="5.0">
 <info>
  <title>Statement of Work</title>
  <subtitle>METS/ALTO Production for Blue Mountain Project Batches 1-5</subtitle>
  <author>
   <orgname>Princeton University Library</orgname>
  </author>
  <revhistory>
   <revision>
    <date>February 21, 2013</date>
    <authorinitials>CEW</authorinitials>
    <revremark>First circulating draft.</revremark>
   </revision>
   <revision>
    <date>May 17, 2013</date>
    <authorinitials>CEW</authorinitials>
    <revremark>Second circulating draft.</revremark>
   </revision>
   <revision>
    <date>October 16, 2013</date>
    <authorinitials>CEW</authorinitials>
    <revremark>This draft is a major change. It recapitulates the work done by
    DDD to date, the prices DDD charges for that work, and the criteria under
    which PUL will accept that work.  It does not address or govern future
    work.</revremark>
   </revision>
  </revhistory>
  <abstract>
   <para>This document formalizes the commitments between Princeton University
   Library (PUL) and Digital Divide Data (DDD) (the Parties) for work already
   done pursuant to NEH grant PW-51046-12.  It supercedes all prior statements
   of work and production schedules, whether produced by DDD or by PUL, in
   whatever form.</para>
  </abstract>
 </info>

 <sect1>
   <title>Billed Work to Date</title>
   <sect2>
     <title>Batches 1-3</title>
     <para>DDD has billed PUL for the METS/ALTO conversion of 12,609 pages at
     a rate of $.56/page (invoice #4172), subject to passing inspection by PUL
     according to the acceptance criteria below.</para>

     <para>This work meets the acceptance criteria.</para>
   </sect2>
   <sect2>
     <title>Batch 4</title>
     <para>DDD has billed PUL for the METS/ALTO conversion of 18,103 pages at
     a rate of $.70/page (invoice #4209), subject to passing inspection by PUL
     according to the acceptance criteria below.</para>

     <para>This work meets the acceptance criteria.</para>
   </sect2>
 </sect1>
 <sect1>
   <title>Work in Progress: Batch 5</title>
   <para>DDD is actively engaged in converting approximately 5,544 pages to
   METS/ALTO.  The price for this work shall be $.70/page, and payment will be
   dependent upon the work meeting the acceptance criteria below.</para>
 </sect1>
 <sect1>
  <title>Acceptance Criteria</title>
  <orderedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para> METS/ALTO data will meet the following criteria: <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
       <para>All identifiers are present and accurate.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>The MODS descriptive metadata meets the specifications detailed in the reference
        document.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>The technical metadata is accurate, and conforms with the specifications detailed in
        the reference document.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>The file data (the fileSec) conforms with the specifications.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>The logical and physical structMap elements are consistent with the docWorks
        configuration AND conform with the specifications outlined in the reference document and any
        markup policies agreed to by both parties.</para>
      </listitem>
     </orderedlist>
    </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>OCR accuracy meets or exceeds the standards established by agreement among the
     parties.</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>All image derivatives conform with the specifications detailed in the reference
     document.</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>All PDF derivatives conform with the specifications detailed in the reference
     document.</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>All file names, directory names, and general organization of files as delivered conform
     with the specifications detailed in the reference document.</para>
   </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
  <sect2>
   <title>Quality Control Guidelines</title>
   <variablelist>
    <title>Definitions</title>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Article Segmentation</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>The division of an article or other text across columns or pages; in digitization, the
       process of analyzing these divisions and encoding it in metadata.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Batch</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>A segment of the total set of titles processed by DDD as a unit. Batches are identified
       and enumerated on tracking sheets shared by DDD and Princeton.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Entry Operator</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>DDD staff member responsible for converting raw image files into required output files
       using docWorks.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Issue Metadata</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>The title, volume, issue, date, and page number order of an issue.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Quality Criteria</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>The critical requirements metrics and standards as described here, including accuracy
       rates and criteria for acceptance or rejection of work produced.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Quality Control (QC)</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>The procedures used by DDD to ensure compliance with the established quality
       standards.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Quality Evaluation and Acceptance (QEA)</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>The procedures used by Princeton University to apply acceptance criteria to work
       produced by DDD.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>QC Operator</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>A member of DDD’s quality control team.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
    <varlistentry>
     <term>Significant Error</term>
     <listitem>
      <para>A discrepancy between the source copy as represented on a page image and the
       computer-readable text output produced by DDD that is counted when calculating error rates
       for compliance with quality standards.</para>
     </listitem>
    </varlistentry>
   </variablelist>

   <orderedlist>
    <title>Quality Standards</title>

    <listitem>
     <para>Headlines and bylines will be 99.95% free of significant errors.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
     <para>Issue metadata will be 99.95% free of significant errors.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
     <para>Body text (defined as text occurring in articles, editorials and other printed material
      but not advertisements) will be 90% free of significant errors.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
     <para>Article segmentation will be 99% free of significant errors.</para>
    </listitem>

    <listitem>
     <para>The XML files produced during digitization will be well-formed and valid against the
      following schemas where appropriate:</para>
     <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
       <para>http://schema.ccs-gmbh.com/docworks/alto-1-2.xsd</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>http://schema.ccs-gmbh.com/docworks/mets-docWORKS.xsd</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>http://www.w3.org/TR/xlink</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>http://www.loc.gov/mix</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns# </para>
      </listitem>
     </orderedlist>
    </listitem>
   </orderedlist>

   <orderedlist>
    <title>Significant Errors</title>
    <listitem>
     <para>incorrect characters (e.g., c for e) </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>transposed characters (e.g., teh for the) </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>missing characters (e.g., tht for that) </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>inserted characters (e.g., c a t for cat) </para>
    </listitem>
   </orderedlist>

   <orderedlist>
    <title>Non-Significant Errorst</title>
    <listitem>
     <para>differences in capitalization (gOlD is equivalent to Gold) </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>padded spacing (more than one whitespace character when original has only one) </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>line breaks</para>
    </listitem>
   </orderedlist>
  </sect2>
  <sect2>
   <title>Quality Evaluation Guidelines</title>
   <para>When DDD has completed a batch, it shall submit output to Princeton for ingestion into
    Princeton's Veridian installation.</para>

   <para>Upon receipt of a batch, Princeton will have 30 days to accept or reject it. Princeton will
    employ the following procedures to evaluate a batch.</para>

   <procedure>
    <step>
     <title>Evaluation of Zoning and Segmentation</title>
     <para> Princeton will examine five (5) issues for zoning and segmentation errors. A zoning or
      segmentation error shall be identified using the following criteria: </para>
     <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
       <para>If an article is missing one or more zones, that shall count as an error.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>If an article contains one or more zones that are not part of the article in the
        original, it shall be counted as an error.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
       <para>If the sequence of zoned regions is not in the proper order, it shall count as an
        error.</para>
      </listitem>
     </orderedlist>
    </step>
   </procedure>

   <para>Princeton will record the results of these examinations in its report. If significant
    errors are discovered, Princeton and DDD will confer.</para>

   <procedure>
    <title>Evaluation of Headlines</title>
    <step>
     <para>Princeton will draw a random sample of 350 headlines from the batch and measure their
      accuracy by comparing each headline with its original and recording all significant errors.
      The accuracy rate of the sample should meet or exceed 99.95%.</para>
    </step>
   </procedure>
   <procedure>
    <title>Evaluation of Body Text</title>
    <step>
     <para>Princeton will examine the fifth article in every sample (as above) for errors in the
      body text, counting the number of significant errors that occur, where significance is as
      defined above. </para>
     <para>We shall assume an average article length of 500 words. For an accuracy rate of 90% or
      better an article should therefore contain no more than 50 significant errors.</para>
     <para>Princeton and DDD shall agree that if more than 5% of the samples from a given batch
      fail, the batch is not acceptable.</para>
    </step>
   </procedure>
   <procedure>
    <title>Evaluation of Metadata</title>
    <step>
     <para>Princeton will evaluate 1 random 2,000 character sampling of Issue Metadata. If the
      sample contains more than 1 error (i.e., it falls below 99.95%), the issue metadata fails and
      must be rechecked and resubmitted by DDD.</para>
    </step>
   </procedure>
   <procedure>
    <title>Evaluation of XML</title>
    <step>
     <para>Princeton will not verify XML validity, as docWorks automatically validates the files it
      produces against the appropriate schemas.</para>
    </step>
   </procedure>
  </sect2>
 </sect1>
 <sect1>
  <title>Notes to Pricing</title>
  <para> Client shall pay DDD all amounts due as provided above. Since the actual number of output
   characters, pages, records and the like may differ from the parties' best estimates made as of
   the date of this Agreement, it is understood and agreed the final Price due shall be based upon
   the actual amount of Work delivered to Client by DDD. </para>
 </sect1>

 <sect1>
  <title>Terms and Conditions</title>
  <orderedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>Both parties agree that this Agreement commits them only to the Work outlined in
     this Agreement, and not to any additional work.</para>
   </listitem>

   <listitem>
    <para>PUL shall be responsible to pay for any sales, use or other taxes due as a result of
     this Agreement or the Work.</para>
   </listitem>

   <listitem>
    <para>This Agreement shall be governed and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of
     New York.</para>
   </listitem>

   <listitem>
    <para>Neither party shall be liable for any delay or default in the performance of this
     Agreement if such delay is due to Acts of God or acts of war, insurrections, riots, fires,
     explosions, governmental order or regulation or other causes reasonably beyond the control of
     the parties. In the event of such delay, the parties agree to promptly discuss the appropriate
     steps to be taken as the result of such delay. </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>DDD agrees to promptly correct any defects or mistakes that it makes in the Work at no
     charge to PUL for a period of sixty (60) days following the completion of the Work. </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>DDD shall be responsible for loss or damage to any of PUL’s property which is caused by
     DDD; provided, however, in no event shall DDD's liability under this Agreement or in any way
     connected with the Work exceed the Price paid by Client to DDD for the Work pursuant to this
     Agreement. </para>
   </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
 </sect1>


 <sect1>
  <title> Representation and Warranties </title>

  <para> Client represents and warrants the following: </para>
  <orderedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para> Client owns the copyright or has permission to copy any data or materials ("Materials")
     that it submits for Servicing; </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>The Materials are not unlawful, threatening, abusive, defamatory, obscene or invade
     another person's privacy or further the commission or concealment of a crime; </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Client is lawfully authorized to transmit the Materials; and </para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>The Materials are not the subject of, or infringe upon, any patent, trademark, trade name,
     trade secret, copyright, right of publicity, moral right or other intellectual property right
     of another person or entity. </para>
   </listitem>
  </orderedlist>
 </sect1>

 <sect1>

  <title>Mediation and Arbitration </title>

  <para> In the event of a dispute under this Agreement, the parties agree to submit such dispute to
   non-binding mediation and to use their best efforts in resolving such a dispute through
   mediation. In the event the parties are unable to resolve such a dispute through mediation, then
   such dispute or other controversy arising under or in connection with this Agreement shall be
   settled exclusively by Arbitration conducted before an Arbitrator in accordance with the rules of
   the American Arbitration Association then in effect. Said Arbitration shall be held in New York,
   New York. The decision of the Arbitrator shall be final and binding on both parties and their
   heirs and legal representatives. Judgment may be entered upon the Arbitrator’s award in any court
   located in New York, New York. Each party shall be responsible to pay for its own costs in
   connection with the Arbitration and the parties shall bear the costs of Arbitration itself and
   the mediation in equal shares. </para>
 </sect1>
 <sect1>

  <title> Successors and Assigns </title>
  <para> The parties agree that this Agreement shall be binding upon and inure to the benefit of
   each of the parties hereto and their successors and assigns. </para>
 </sect1>
 <sect1>
  <title>Cooperation</title>
  <para> Each party hereto agrees to cooperate with the other in carrying out the terms of this
   Agreement. In connection therewith, each party agrees to execute such documents and take such
   steps as may be necessary or advisable to carry out the purposes of this Agreement, whether
   before or after the date of this Agreement. </para>
 </sect1>


 <sect1>
  <title>Communication</title>
  <table>
   <title>Escalation Table</title>
   <tgroup cols="3">
    <thead>
     <row>
      <entry>Level</entry>
      <entry>PUL</entry>
      <entry>DDD</entry>
     </row>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
     <row>
      <entry>Level 1</entry>
      <entry>
       <para>
        <personname>Natalia Ermolaev</personname>
        <variablelist>
         <title/>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>Project Manager</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Phone</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>609-258-6243</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Email</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>nataliae@Princeton.EDU</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Skype</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>Natalia</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
       </para>
      </entry>
      <entry>
       <para>
        <personname>Rady ROS</personname>
        <variablelist>
         <title/>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>Project Manager</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Phone</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>+855.23.220.843</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Email</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>rady.ros@digitaldividedata.org</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Skype</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>radyros</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
       </para>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry>Level 2</entry>
      <entry>
       <para>
        <personname>Clifford Wulfman</personname>
        <variablelist>
         <title/>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>Project Director</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Phone</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>609-258-7290</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Email</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>cwulfman@Princeton.EDU</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Skype</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>thecoldi</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
       </para>
      </entry>
      <entry>
       <para>
        <personname>Jason Judd</personname>
        <variablelist>
         <title/>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>Snr. Director Production</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Phone</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>+855.23.220.843</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Email</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>jason.judd@digitaldividedata.org</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Skype</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>jasonjudd</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
       </para>
      </entry>
     </row>
     <row>
      <entry>Level 3</entry>
      <entry>
       <para>
        <personname>Marvin Bielawski</personname>
        <variablelist>
         <title/>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>Deputy University Librarian</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Phone</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>609-258-3190</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Email</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>marvinb@Princeton.EDU</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
       </para>
      </entry>
      <entry>
       <para>
        <personname>Jeremy Hokenstein</personname>
        <variablelist>
         <title/>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Title</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>CEO</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Phone</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>212-461-3703</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
         <varlistentry>
          <term>Email</term>
          <listitem>
           <para>jeremy@digitaldividedata.org</para>
          </listitem>
         </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>
       </para>
      </entry>
     </row>
    </tbody>
   </tgroup>
  </table>
 </sect1>
</article>
