<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
	 version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>Statement of Work</title>
    <subtitle>METS/ALTO Production for Phase I of the Blue Mountain
    Project</subtitle>
    <author>
      <orgname>Princeton University Library</orgname>
    </author>
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
	<date>February 21, 2013</date>
	<authorinitials>CEW</authorinitials>
	<revremark>First circulating draft.</revremark>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
    <abstract>
      <para>The Statement of Work agreement between Princeton
      University Library (PUL) and Digital Divide Data (DDD) for the
      remaining portion of the Blue Mountain Project, Phase I. It
      supercedes all prior statements of work and production
      schedules, whether produced by DDDD or by PUL, in whatever
      form.</para>
    </abstract>
  </info>
  <sect1>
    <title>Rationale</title>

    <para> The total page count for Blue Mountain, Phase I is
    approximately 92,305. The grant cycle for Phase I ends on
    September 1, 2014, and production should be completed well before
    then. The following schedule, then, is based on 7 two-month
    production cycles for Digital Divide Data, where a cycle is
    defined in the plan of work below. </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Reference Documents</title>
    <para> The Blue Mountain Project has detailed its policies,
    requirements, and formats in a Reference Document, maintained and
    distributed on the wiki at the Blue Mountain Project's GitHub
    portal <link
    xlink:href="https://github.com/pulibrary/BlueMountain"
    >https://github.com/pulibrary/BlueMountain</link>. </para>
  </sect1>

  <sect1>
    <title>Plan of Work</title>
    <para>The Work shall be divided into discrete units (hereafter
    referred to as batches, deliveries, or tranches), as defined in
    the section below.  Processing of each unit shall follow this
    procedure:
    </para>

    <procedure>
      <title>Processing Procedure</title>

      <step>
	<para>For each unit, PUL shall provide DDD with the following
	items:</para>
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <formalpara>
	      <title>LZW-Compressed TIFF Files</title>
	      <para>For each title, PUL shall provide image files in the
	      format specified in the reference document. PUL shall
	      arrange these image files into systems of directories
	      (folders) organized by date of publication, as specified in
	      the reference document. Princeton shall make every
	      reasonable effort to ensure these issue sets are accurate
	      and complete. If, upon DDD's inspection at receipt, there
	      are missing pages, duplicate pages, or other directory-level
	      or file-level anomalies which impede or otherwise interfere
	      with DDD's subsequent processing of the materials, DDD shall
	      inform Princeton immediately for remedy. Princeton shall not
	      be responsible for redundant work performed by DDD in remedy
	      of such anomalies.  These page-image files shall be
	      delivered via one of two media, subject to negotiation:

	      <orderedlist>
		<listitem><para>File transfer via Box.com.  This is
		preferred.</para></listitem>
		
		<listitem><para>Portable hard drive, shipped to DDD in
		Cambodia via FedEx.  If the hard drive option is chosen,
		DDD will absorb the cost of shipping.</para></listitem>
	      </orderedlist>
	      </para>
	    </formalpara>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <formalpara>
	      <title>Title-Specific Markup Policies</title>
	      <para>For each title, PUL shall provide the following:
	      <orderedlist>
		<listitem>
		  <para>A title-specific markup addendum clarifying
		  unusual zoning and structural features;</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>A sample copy (in PDF format) marked up according
		  to the markup policy;</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
		  <para>A marked up copy of any issue(s) deviating
		  substantially from either the general or title-specific
		  markup policies.</para>
		</listitem>
	      </orderedlist>
	      DDD shall work with PUL to produce these items.
	      Modifications to the markup instructions or changes to
	      the Blue Mountain docWorks configuration must be
	      completed before DDD begins work on the batch.
	      </para>

	    </formalpara>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
      	    <formalpara>
	      <title>Descriptive Metadata for each Issue</title>
	      <para>PUL shall prepare provide title, volume and issue
	      numbers and labels, dates of publication, and the
	      identifiers required by Blue Mountain as described in the
	      reference document.  PUL will deliver this metadata in MODS
	      format, as described in the reference document (The Metadata
	      Store).  PUL will maintain the metadata store in the Blue
	      Mountain Github repository; DDD shall be responsible for
	      retrieving these files from the Blue Mountain GitHub
	      repository and for updating their local copies should
	      changes become necessary after production of a batch begins.</para>
	    </formalpara>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </step>
      <step>
	<para>
	  DDD shall process the page images and descriptive metadata into
	  METS/ALTO, JPEG2000, and PDF outputs (the PRODUCT) according to
	  the Blue Mountain docWorks configuration.
	</para>
      </step>
      <step>
	<para>
	  DDD shall deliver the Product to Princeton via one of the
	  authorized transmission media, as specified above.
	</para>
      </step>
      <step>
	<para>
	  DDD shall issue an invoice to Princeton for EXACTLY the work
	  performed in fulfillment of this batch.  The Blue Mountain
	  Project will not accept invoices that fail to specify, in
	  detail, the work being billed, or that bill for work that spans
	  discrete batches, or that entail work done for other
	  Princeton-related projects.
	</para>
      </step>
      <step>
	<para>Princeton shall ingest the Product into its
	content-management system and the Veridian content-delivery
	system.  Princeton shall evaluate the Product, in its raw form
	and in its deployed form, and shall notify DDD in a timely
	fashion of any anomalies outside the tolerances set forth
	below.
	</para>
      </step>
      <step>
	<para>
	  Princeton shall have 30 days to request corrections.  At the
	  end of 30 days, Princeton shall either (a) accept the work
	  and pay the invoice; or (b) reject the work and delete it
	  from its systems.
	</para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Schedule of Work</title>
    <para>
      The following shall be the agreed-upon schedule of work.  The
      schedule shall be maintained as a set of milestones in the
      Project's Goplan tracking system.
    </para>
    <table frame="all">
      <title>Composition of Blue Mountain Work by Batch</title>
      <tgroup cols="8">
	<colspec colname="c1" colwidth="2*"/>
	<colspec colname="c2" colwidth="1*"/>
	<colspec colname="c3"/>
	<colspec colname="c4"/>
	<colspec colname="c5"/>
	<colspec colname="c6"/>
	<colspec colname="c7"/>
	<colspec colname="c8"/>

	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry></entry>
	    <entry>Jan-Feb</entry>
	    <entry>Feb-Mar</entry>
	    <entry>Apr-May</entry>
	    <entry>Jun-Jul</entry>
	    <entry>Aug-Sep</entry>
	    <entry>Oct-Nov</entry>
	    <entry>Dec-Jan</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>291</entry>
	    <entry>30</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Dada</entry>
	    <entry>94</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Der Sturm</entry>
	    <entry>4959</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>l'elan</entry>
	    <entry>254</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Le coeur à barbe</entry>
	    <entry>8</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Action</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">942</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Broom</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">2550</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Bruno's Weekly</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">1234</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>New Numbers</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">210</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Secession</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">30</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>The Signature</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">100</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Sturm Buhne</entry>
	    <entry namest="c3">32</entry>
	  </row>

	  <row>
	    <entry>MA</entry>
	    <entry namest="c4">700</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Umělecký mĕsíčník</entry>
	    <entry namest="c4">976</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Veshch</entry>
	    <entry namest="c4">172</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Volné směry</entry>
	    <entry namest="c4">13,561</entry>
	  </row>

	  <row>
	    <entry>291</entry>
	    <entry namest="c5">22</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>La Chronique musicale</entry>
	    <entry namest="c5">3,929</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>La Cité</entry>
	    <entry namest="c5">5,271</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>La Revue musicale</entry>
	    <entry namest="c5">5,700</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Surrealisme</entry>
	    <entry namest="c5">16</entry>
	  </row>


	  
	  <row>
	    <entry>Le Mecure musicale</entry>
	    <entry namest="c6">10,327</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Niederrheinische Musik-Zeitung</entry>
	    <entry namest="c6">8,866</entry>
	  </row>

	  <row>
	    <entry>Dalibor</entry>
	    <entry namest="c7">17,425</entry>
	  </row>

	  <row>
	    <entry>East and West</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">600</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>The Glebe</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">618</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Klingen</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">770</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Les Entretien</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">2,871</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>The Mask</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">2370</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Nord-Sud</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">230</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Nowa Sztuka</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">65</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>The Plowshare</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">4,280</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Poesia</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">1652</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Proverbe</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">60</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>SIC</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">448</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Ultra</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">130</entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Zeit-Echo</entry>
	    <entry namest="c8">493</entry>
	  </row>

	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Acceptance Criteria</title>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  METS/ALTO data will meet the following criteria:
	  <orderedlist>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>All identifiers are present and accurate.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>The MODS descriptive metadata meets th
	      specifications detailed in the reference document.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>The technical metadata is accurate, and conforms
	      with the specifications detailed in the reference
	      document.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>The file data (the fileSec) conforms with the specifications.</para>
	    </listitem>
	    <listitem>
	      <para>The logical and physical structMap elements are
	      consistent with the docWorks configuration AND conform
	      with the specifications outlined in the reference
	      document and any markup policies agreed to by both
	      parties.</para>
	    </listitem>
	  </orderedlist>
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>OCR accuracy meets or exceeds the standards established
	by agreement among the parties.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>All image derivatives conform with the specifications
	detailed in the reference document.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>All PDF derivatives conform with the specifications
	detailed in the reference document.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>All file names, directory names, and general
	organization of files as delivered conform with the
	specifications detailed in the reference document.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <sect2>
      <title>Quality Control Guidelines</title>
      <variablelist>
	<title>Definitions</title>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Article Segmentation</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>The division of an article or other text across
	    columns or pages; in digitization, the process of
	    analyzing these divisions and encoding it in
	    metadata.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Batch</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>A segment of the total set of titles processed
	    by DDD as a unit. Batches are identified and enumerated on
	    tracking sheets shared by DDD and Princeton.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Entry Operator</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>DDD staff member responsible for converting raw
	    image files into required output files using
	    docWorks.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	<term>Issue Metadata</term>
	<listitem>
	  <para>The title, volume, issue, date, and page number order
	  of an issue.</para>
	</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Quality Criteria</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>The critical requirements metrics and standards as
	    described here, including accuracy rates and criteria for
	    acceptance or rejection of work produced.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Quality Control (QC)</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>The procedures used by DDD to ensure compliance with
	    the established quality standards.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Quality Evaluation and Acceptance (QEA)</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>The procedures used by Princeton University to apply
	    acceptance criteria to work produced by DDD.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>QC Operator</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>A member of DDD’s quality control team.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Significant Error</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>A discrepancy between the source copy as represented
	    on a page image and the computer-readable text output
	    produced by DDD that is counted when calculating error
	    rates for compliance with quality standards.</para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
      </variablelist>

      <orderedlist>
	<title>Quality Standards</title>

	<listitem><para>Headlines and bylines will be 99.95% free of
	significant errors.</para></listitem>

	<listitem><para>Issue metadata will be 99.95% free of
	significant errors.</para></listitem>

	<listitem><para>Body text (defined as text occurring in
	articles, editorials and other printed material but not
	advertisements) will be 90% free of significant
	errors.</para></listitem>

	<listitem><para>Article segmentation will be 99% free of
	significant errors.</para></listitem>

	<listitem><para>The XML files produced during digitization
	will be well-formed and valid against the following schemas
	where appropriate:</para>
	<orderedlist>
	  <listitem><para>http://schema.ccs-gmbh.com/docworks/alto-1-2.xsd</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>http://schema.ccs-gmbh.com/docworks/mets-docWORKS.xsd</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>http://www.w3.org/TR/xlink</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>http://www.loc.gov/mix</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns# </para></listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <orderedlist>
	<title>Significant Errors</title>
	<listitem><para>incorrect characters (e.g., c for e) </para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>transposed characters (e.g., teh for the) </para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>missing characters (e.g., tht for that) </para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>inserted characters (e.g., c a t for cat) </para></listitem>
      </orderedlist>

      <orderedlist>
	<title>Non-Significant Errorst</title>
	<listitem><para>differences in capitalization (gOlD is
	equivalent to Gold) </para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>padded spacing (more than one whitespace
	character when original has only one) </para></listitem>
	<listitem><para>line breaks</para></listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </sect2>
    <sect2>
    <title>Quality Evaluation Guidelines</title>
    <para>When DDD has completed a batch, it shall submit output to
    Princeton for ingestion into Princeton's Veridian
    installation.</para>

    <para>Upon receipt of a batch, Princeton will have 30 days to
    accept or reject it. Princeton will employ the following
    procedures to evaluate a batch.</para>

    <procedure>
      <step>
	<title>Evaluation of Zoning and Segmentation</title>
	<para>
	  Princeton will examine five (5) issues for zoning and
	  segmentation errors. A zoning or segmentation error shall be
	  identified using the following criteria:
	</para>
	<orderedlist>
	  <listitem><para>If an article is missing one or more zones, that shall
	  count as an error.</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>If an article contains one or more zones that are not
	  part of the article in the original, it shall be counted as an
	  error.</para></listitem>
	  <listitem><para>If the sequence of zoned regions is not in the proper
	  order, it shall count as an error.</para></listitem>
	</orderedlist>
      </step>
    </procedure>

    <para>Princeton will record the results of these examinations in
    its report. If significant errors are discovered, Princeton and
    DDD will confer.</para>

    <procedure>
      <title>Evaluation of Headlines</title>
      <step>
	<para>Princeton will draw a random sample of 350 headlines
	from the batch and measure its accuracy by comparing each
	headline with its original and recording all significant
	errors. The accuracy rate of the sample should meet or exceed
	99.95%.</para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
    <procedure>
      <title>Evaluation of Body Text</title>
      <step>
	<para>Princeton will examine the fifth article in every sample
	(as above) for errors in the body text, counting the number of
	significant errors that occur, where significance is as
	defined above.
	</para>
	<para>We shall assume an average article length of 500
	words. For an accuracy rate of 90% or better an article should
	therefore contain no more than 50 significant errors.</para>
	<para>Princeton and DDD shall agree that if more than 5% of
	the samples from a given batch fail, the batch is not
	acceptable.</para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
    <procedure>
      <title>Evaluation of Metadata</title>
      <step>
	<para>Princeton will evaluate 1 random 2,000 character
	sampling of Issue Metadata. If the sample contains more than 1
	error (i.e., it falls below 99.95%), the issue metadata fails
	and must be rechecked and resubmitted by DDD.</para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
    <procedure>
      <title>Evaluation of XML</title>
      <step>
	<para>Princeton will not verify XML validity, as docWorks
	automatically validates the files it produces against the
	appropriate schemas.</para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
    </sect2>
  </sect1>
  <sect1>
    <title>Communication</title>
    <table>
      <title>Escalation Table</title>
      <tgroup cols="3">
	<thead>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Level</entry>
	    <entry>PUL</entry>
	    <entry>DDD</entry>
	  </row>
	</thead>
	<tbody>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Level 1</entry>
	    <entry>
	      <para>
		<personname>Natalia Ermolaev</personname>
		<variablelist>
		  <title/>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Title</term>
		    <listitem><para>Project Manager</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Phone</term>
		    <listitem><para>609-258-6243</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Email</term>
		    <listitem><para>nataliae@Princeton.EDU</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Skype</term>
		    <listitem><para>Natalia</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	      </para>
	    </entry>
	    <entry>
	      <para>
		<personname>Rady ROS</personname>
		<variablelist>
		  <title/>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Title</term>
		    <listitem><para>Project Manager</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Phone</term>
		    <listitem><para>+855.23.220.843</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Email</term>
		    <listitem><para>rady.ros@digitaldividedata.org</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Skype</term>
		    <listitem><para>radyros</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	      </para>
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Level 2</entry>
	    <entry>
	      <para>
		<personname>Clifford Wulfman</personname>
		<variablelist>
		  <title/>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Title</term>
		    <listitem><para>Project Director</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Phone</term>
		    <listitem><para>609-258-7290</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Email</term>
		    <listitem><para>cwulfman@Princeton.EDU</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Skype</term>
		    <listitem><para>thecoldi</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	      </para>
	    </entry>
	    <entry>
	      <para>
		<personname>Jason Judd</personname>
		<variablelist>
		  <title/>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Title</term>
		    <listitem><para>Snr. Director Production</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Phone</term>
		    <listitem><para>+855.23.220.843</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Email</term>
		    <listitem><para>jason.judd@digitaldividedata.org</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Skype</term>
		    <listitem><para>jasonjudd</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	      </para>
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	  <row>
	    <entry>Level 3</entry>
	    <entry>
	      <para>
		<personname>Marvin Bielawski</personname>
		<variablelist>
		  <title/>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Title</term>
		    <listitem><para>Deputy University Librarian</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Phone</term>
		    <listitem><para>609-258-3190</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Email</term>
		    <listitem><para>marvinb@Princeton.EDU</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	      </para>
	    </entry>
	    <entry>
	      <para>
		<personname>Jeremy Hokenstein</personname>
		<variablelist>
		  <title/>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Title</term>
		    <listitem><para>CEO</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Phone</term>
		    <listitem><para>212-461-3703</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		  <varlistentry>
		    <term>Email</term>
		    <listitem><para>jeremy@digitaldividedata.org</para></listitem>
		  </varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
	      </para>
	    </entry>
	  </row>
	</tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </sect1>
</article>
